<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>debian on </title>
    <link>https://cmdln.org/tags/debian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in debian on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 15:04:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cmdln.org/tags/debian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Keychain: a love once forgotten now found</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2010/04/07/keychain-a-love-once-forgotten-now-found/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 15:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2010/04/07/keychain-a-love-once-forgotten-now-found/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;#8217;t know how many of you know that I am a recovering gentoo user. One of the staples of my desktop used to be keychain. Keychain is a simple wrapper for ssh-agent and gpg-agent. It eases the use of a single long running agent per system instead of per login session. For some reason this tool had fallen out of my basket when I switched to debian several years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debian adopting time based freeze</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2009/08/01/debian-adopting-time-based-freeze/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 18:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2009/08/01/debian-adopting-time-based-freeze/</guid>
      <description>Debian is departing (if ever so slightly) from the historical mantra &amp;#8220;It ships when its ready&amp;#8221;.
Looks as if Debian has decided time based freeze schedules will help them better manage time. Note they are not adopting time based releases, only the freeze is time based. I personally think this is a good thing. It will still ship when its ready but at least there will be some semblance of a time line for new releases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debian /etc/cron.d/ gotcha</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2008/11/19/debian-etccrond-gotcha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 14:57:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2008/11/19/debian-etccrond-gotcha/</guid>
      <description>I typically use /etc/cron.d to store all of my system crontabs. I recently ran into an issue that I had either not run into before, or fixed and paid no attention to. Files stored in /etc/cron.d/ or any /etc/cron.* directory need to adhear to the run-parts Debian cron script namespace which consists is
(^[a-z0-9][a-z0-9-]*$)  for the regex impared this does not include the dot character. If you have a file in /etc/cron.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purge previously uninstalled packages in debian</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2008/04/18/purge-previously-uninstalled-packages-in-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 05:33:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2008/04/18/purge-previously-uninstalled-packages-in-debian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I ordered a server with Debian etch. Unfortunately during testing I noticed that startx was on the system, along with a whole slew of other junk that I don&amp;#8217;t generally want on a fresh server. I wanted to remove all of the cruft but I didn&amp;#8217;t have the exact package list.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>