<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Logging on </title>
    <link>http://www.cmdln.org/tags/logging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Logging on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2010 15:17:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.cmdln.org/tags/logging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flashback: Remote kernel logging with netconsole for fun and profit</title>
      <link>http://www.cmdln.org/2010/03/05/flashback-remote-kernel-logging-with-netconsole-for-fun-and-profit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2010 15:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cmdln.org/2010/03/05/flashback-remote-kernel-logging-with-netconsole-for-fun-and-profit/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever had a machine that was a bit flaky? You know those ones that occasionally crash and don&amp;#8217;t write anything useful into the log file. Sometimes you can capture those messages with netconsole. Just revisiting a small walk-through I wrote a while back.
Remote kernel logging with netconsole for fun and profit</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote kernel logging with netconsole for fun and profit</title>
      <link>http://www.cmdln.org/2009/01/21/remote-kernel-logging-with-netconsole-for-fun-and-profit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2009 16:36:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cmdln.org/2009/01/21/remote-kernel-logging-with-netconsole-for-fun-and-profit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever experienced hard lockups and seen no trace of the cause in your log files? Those situations can be even more of a pain if you do not have physical access to the machine since you will not be able to look for kernel oops on the console. You could buy a serial console or an ip kvm but if you don&amp;#8217;t have the need for remote control, but would really like to be able to debug without being physically present you need to check out netconsole. Netconsole sends printk messages over UDP. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic session logging and monitoring with GNU screen for the paranoid.</title>
      <link>http://www.cmdln.org/2007/07/20/automatic-session-logging-and-monitoring-with-gnu-screen-for-the-paranoid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2007 14:07:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cmdln.org/2007/07/20/automatic-session-logging-and-monitoring-with-gnu-screen-for-the-paranoid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yes its been a while since I have checked in. Sorry I&amp;#8217;ve just been too busy. But I have a great tip this time. Recently I had the need to do automatic session logging. A 3rd party was going to be logging into one of my servers to check out some software glitches that were happening. I love using GNU Screen for many shell tasks so using it for monitoring was logical. Screen is great for several reasons. First you can detach from it so you can leave the office, go home and re-attach and not have lost your place. Second, you can share another screen. It can be shared input or you can just watch what someone else is doing. Finally screen can do native logging. I wanted to automattically launch a screen session when somone logged in so if I happened to be on the server I could monitor them in real time. I also wanted a log of the session in case I wanted to look over it later or if I was not able to monitor the session live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>