<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nagios on </title>
    <link>https://cmdln.org/tags/nagios/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nagios on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 03:39:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cmdln.org/tags/nagios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SNMP v3 support added to check_snmp_extend.py</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2011/07/04/snmp-v3-support-added-to-check_snmp_extend-py/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 03:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2011/07/04/snmp-v3-support-added-to-check_snmp_extend-py/</guid>
      <description>check_snmp_extend is a python script that I found orphaned on some Nagios forum. It facilitates using snmpd as an agent for executing Nagios plugin scripts. I adopted it made a few changes and tossed it on github a while back. I&amp;#8217;m happy to merge initial snmp v3 support from Lee Whalen</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CheckDomain Zenpack</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2010/07/12/checkdomain-zenpack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 15:52:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2010/07/12/checkdomain-zenpack/</guid>
      <description>No one likes to forget to renew a domain. Its not wholly uncommon though. Microsoft forgot to renew passport.com in 1999, and hotmail.co.uk in 2003. Vivendi Universal forgot to renew its MP3.com in 2003, the Washington Post forgot to renew in 2004, and Foursquare forgot to renew their domain in 2010.
I stumbled on the check_domain nagios plugin this weekend so I figured I would make some quick modifications and roll it into a Zenpack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sysstat Sar Performance Metrics Via Nagios Plugin</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2010/03/09/sysstat-sar-performance-metrics-via-nagios-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 15:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2010/03/09/sysstat-sar-performance-metrics-via-nagios-plugin/</guid>
      <description>I know I&amp;#8217;ve mentioned how much I love the sysstat package before. I use sar regularly to help with performance diagnostics (Analyzing Linux System Performance And Finding Bottle Necks, CPU Performance Analysis In Linux, Baseline Analysis Is Important, CPU Performance Analysis In Linux Revisited). I wrote this little Nagios plugin to collect the performance metrics that sar collects.
I use this plugin with Zenoss and I set any performance thresholds there, more important to me was collecting the information for historical graphing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XenServer License Check &amp;#8211; Nagios NRPE Plugin</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2010/03/08/xenserver-license-check-nagios-nrpe-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2010 14:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2010/03/08/xenserver-license-check-nagios-nrpe-plugin/</guid>
      <description>If you hadn&amp;#8217;t already guessed I am a big fan of the Xen hypervisor. Lately I have been using the Citrix XenServer release because it makes it quite palatable for my co-workers. One annoyance that I do have about XenServer is the requirement that you license it (with a free license) every year. If you fail to license it the GUI stops working. Now I hate relying on GUIs but the fact of the matter is others in my team expect to have a working GUI when they need to do something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing NRPE on XenServer</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2010/03/04/installing-nrpe-on-xenserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2010 18:05:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2010/03/04/installing-nrpe-on-xenserver/</guid>
      <description>I like to have as little run in dom0 as possible. However some things you really need checked from dom0, like the status of your raid perhaps. Just some quick instructions on getting Nagios NRPE running in XenServer.
 Install EPEL repository and disable it by default (remember we don&amp;#8217;t want to accidentally install unnecessary packages) wget http://download.fedora.redhat.com/pub/epel/5/$(uname -i)/epel-release-5-3.noarch.rpm rpm -hiv epel-release*.rpm sed -i &amp;rsquo;s/enabled=1/enabled=0/g&amp;rsquo; /etc/yum.repos.d/epel.repo 
 Install nrpe and configure it to start on boot yum install &amp;ndash;enablerepo=epel nrpe chkconfig nrpe on</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>