<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Screen on </title>
    <link>https://cmdln.org/tags/screen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Screen on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 14:31:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cmdln.org/tags/screen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flashback: Automatic session logging and monitoring with GNU screen for the paranoid</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2010/03/02/flashback-automatic-session-logging-and-monitoring-with-gnu-screen-for-the-paranoid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 14:31:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2010/03/02/flashback-automatic-session-logging-and-monitoring-with-gnu-screen-for-the-paranoid/</guid>
      <description>Another day, another flashback. I don&amp;#8217;t know about you but at times I have had some very odd and uncomfortable requests from vendors. It&amp;#8217;s not wholly uncommon for them to want to log into your system to diagnose an issue for themselves. Or perhaps for whatever reason your manager says hey give this random outside person access to some important box. As a SA you get used to extremely odd requests and figure out how to just solve the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I tamed my mutt</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2008/11/07/how-i-tamed-my-mutt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2008 04:09:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2008/11/07/how-i-tamed-my-mutt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you by now well know I try to mostly live at the console (well multiple x consoles). Mutt is my mail client of choice. I&amp;#8217;ve tried Thunderbird, Kmail, Evolution, Sylpheed, and pine. For whatever reason I feel most comfortable with mutt. I also use IMAP for both my personal and work accounts. Mutt was originally designed to deal with local mail and while it does a very good job with IMAP I don&amp;#8217;t like how it handles multiple accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Console sharing without setuid gnu screen</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2008/08/25/console-sharing-without-setuid-gnu-screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2008 21:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2008/08/25/console-sharing-without-setuid-gnu-screen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I mentioned in my last post &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cmdln.org/2008/08/13/shared-console-sessions/&#34;&gt;Shared console sessions&lt;/a&gt; that I would have an update to get near same functionality without setuid of the screen binary. Well here it is. Hopefully you are aware of expect and how it can be used to automate interactive programs like telnet. Expect is has many more uses that people are exploiting. Enter kibitz. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shared console sessions</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2008/08/13/shared-console-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 01:14:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2008/08/13/shared-console-sessions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had several posts regarding screen. Hopefully you have already realized the greatness of screen. Screen has a great feature that allows screen sessions to be shared. To my knowledge there are two ways to use this feature. First you can connect to a screen multiple times as the same user. Second you can use the multiuser mode of screen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spice up your bash prompt redux | A nice .screenrc redux with screencast</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2008/02/24/spice-up-your-bash-prompt-redux-a-nice-screenrc-redux-with-screencast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 05:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2008/02/24/spice-up-your-bash-prompt-redux-a-nice-screenrc-redux-with-screencast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is more or less going to be an addendum to my last post as well as an update to my previous screenrc post. About 5 minutes after posting I realized that my additions to my prompt broke some new additions to new screenrc settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A nice .screenrc</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2008/02/08/a-nice-screenrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2008 14:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2008/02/08/a-nice-screenrc/</guid>
      <description>Hopefully you already know about screen, its one of the best command line utilites I use. Here is a purty screenrc for you.
.screenrc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix terminal scrolling when inside GNU Screen</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2007/07/31/fix-terminal-scrolling-when-inside-gnu-screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2007 17:52:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2007/07/31/fix-terminal-scrolling-when-inside-gnu-screen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My post on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cmdln.org/2007/07/20/automatic-session-logging-and-monitoring-with-gnu-screen-for-the-paranoid/&#34; mce_href=&#34;http://www.cmdln.org/2007/07/20/automatic-session-logging-and-monitoring-with-gnu-screen-for-the-paranoid/&#34;&gt; Automatic session logging and monitoring with GNU screen&lt;/a&gt; seems to have been well received. I have had more hits by far on that post today than ever before. I noticed a nagging issue with screen and a friend of mine Travis Cline pointed me to the fix. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic session logging and monitoring with GNU screen for the paranoid.</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2007/07/20/automatic-session-logging-and-monitoring-with-gnu-screen-for-the-paranoid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2007 14:07:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2007/07/20/automatic-session-logging-and-monitoring-with-gnu-screen-for-the-paranoid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yes its been a while since I have checked in. Sorry I&amp;#8217;ve just been too busy. But I have a great tip this time. Recently I had the need to do automatic session logging. A 3rd party was going to be logging into one of my servers to check out some software glitches that were happening. I love using GNU Screen for many shell tasks so using it for monitoring was logical. Screen is great for several reasons. First you can detach from it so you can leave the office, go home and re-attach and not have lost your place. Second, you can share another screen. It can be shared input or you can just watch what someone else is doing. Finally screen can do native logging. I wanted to automattically launch a screen session when somone logged in so if I happened to be on the server I could monitor them in real time. I also wanted a log of the session in case I wanted to look over it later or if I was not able to monitor the session live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>