<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bash on </title>
    <link>https://cmdln.org/tags/bash/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bash on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 May 2010 15:14:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cmdln.org/tags/bash/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>bash history-fu</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2010/05/20/bash-historyfu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2010 15:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2010/05/20/bash-historyfu/</guid>
      <description>I came across a new blog (seems to have come on-line in March) http://www.epoxyjournal.com. One of the entries was about how to clear command history. Everyone has inadvertently pasted or typed something into the wrong shell. Sometimes its worthwhile to clean up after yourself and sometimes its not. I figured I would offer a suggestion for the times you want to avoid having your embarrassing moments in your ~/.bash_history.
Instead of blowing away your entire current buffer with history -c you can redirect it to another file, flush the buffer to the file, clean it up then append it to your ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert maildir to mbox</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2009/03/13/convert-maildir-to-mbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2009 16:52:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2009/03/13/convert-maildir-to-mbox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note, there is a short story before the main course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently had a customer leave. It’s never good to lose a customer. They left not because of any service issues but because its hard for them to understand that I am not a web designer. I provided hosting service for them, and I tried to make it clear that they should find a web desinger and someone to maintain their site because that is not something I specialize in or have any interest in doing. At any rate this of course leads to them finding a designer who wants to move their site to some other host. I have no problems with that whatever makes the maintainer happy since he is the one&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notify someone with hook when you update a git working copy</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2008/12/06/notify-someone-with-hook-when-you-update-a-git-working-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 05:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2008/12/06/notify-someone-with-hook-when-you-update-a-git-working-copy/</guid>
      <description>Some projects have production code that runs off of a git cloned repository. There may be a case in which you want to notify others when that clone pulls. It is a pretty easy feat with gits post-merge hook. The post-merge hook will run after a merge (think git pull). All you have to do it create a project/.git/hooks/post-merge shell script and chmod +x it. Next time you pull successfully that script will run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmark hard drive performance in Linux</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2008/04/26/benchmark-hard-drive-performance-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2008 19:41:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2008/04/26/benchmark-hard-drive-performance-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bonnie is a great tool to use to benchmark your file system. Just a quick tip on using bonnie.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Match string and print preceding line</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2008/04/10/match-string-and-print-preceding-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2008 19:59:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2008/04/10/match-string-and-print-preceding-line/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Text processing is fun. Well, fun if you like to beat your head against a wall. Most of the time I just string a few things together to get whatever I am doing done. Its much better to find the shortest way to do something, it spawns less processes, is more efficient and generally a good idea. So if you have ever wanted to match a string from some given output and only print the preceding line here you go.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SyntaxHighlighter Plus Patch</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2008/04/07/syntaxhighlighter-plus-patch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2008 06:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2008/04/07/syntaxhighlighter-plus-patch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: I did not write the bash support for &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/syntaxhighlighter/&#34; title=&#34;syntaxhighlighter&#34;&gt;syntaxhighlighter&lt;/a&gt; bboy.mr.freeze did and it can also be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://bboy.mr.freeze.googlepages.com/shBrushBash.js&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; . All I did was take that, and modify &lt;a href=&#34;http://thislab.com/2007/12/16/release-wordpress-plugin-syntaxhighlighter-plus/&#34;&gt;SyntaxHighlighter Plus&lt;/a&gt; to take advantage of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spice up your bash prompt</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2008/02/24/spice-up-your-bash-prompt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 03:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2008/02/24/spice-up-your-bash-prompt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spend a lot of my time sitting in front of terminals if you have not yet guessed. When dealing with different user accounts across different systems and a plethora of terminals open its nice to have a bit of information about who you are, and where you are. I also like to be able to easily differentiate output from different commands. If your interested read on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
