<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Centos on </title>
    <link>https://nickanderson.github.io/tags/centos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Centos on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2012 04:55:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nickanderson.github.io/tags/centos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New bundle to manage routes for RedHat/CentOS with CFEngine 3</title>
      <link>https://nickanderson.github.io/2012/02/18/new-bundle-to-manage-routes-for-redhatcentos-with-cfengine-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2012 04:55:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickanderson.github.io/2012/02/18/new-bundle-to-manage-routes-for-redhatcentos-with-cfengine-3/</guid>
      <description>I re-factored rh_add_interface_routes into a new bundle rh_update_routes, you can find them in my CFEngine library.
The biggest improvement is you no longer have to specify the interface you want the route on. Instead you specify a regular expression of the ip that would be on that interface and the specific interface is found.
Second major improvement is the direct use of ip route del/add to update currently running system instead of restarting all networking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Centos 6 on the horizon</title>
      <link>https://nickanderson.github.io/2011/06/24/centos-6-on-the-horizon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 17:41:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickanderson.github.io/2011/06/24/centos-6-on-the-horizon/</guid>
      <description>Just happened to notice that centos 6 looks like it will be dropping soon. In QA and syncing to internal servers today, sync to public mirrors on Monday.
http://qaweb.dev.centos.org/qa</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persistent ulimit settings in Centos/RH</title>
      <link>https://nickanderson.github.io/2010/04/12/persistent-ulimit-settings-in-centosrh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 15:47:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickanderson.github.io/2010/04/12/persistent-ulimit-settings-in-centosrh/</guid>
      <description>Recently a developer came to me and said they are starting to see failed builds apparently due to open file handle limitations on the build server. In case your not aware, by default there are limitations on users to ensure they don&amp;#8217;t hog the entire resources of a system. Sometimes these limitations need to be adjusted.
In my case the &amp;#8220;bamboo&amp;#8221; user needed more than 1024 open files on occasion. I determined my system had a maximum number of open files of 1572928.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Error Msg Fail: How to enable telnet on centos/rhel</title>
      <link>https://nickanderson.github.io/2010/04/06/error-msg-fail-how-to-enable-telnet-on-centosrhel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2010 14:46:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickanderson.github.io/2010/04/06/error-msg-fail-how-to-enable-telnet-on-centosrhel/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;#8217;t even start with me about how telnet is horrid. Out side of my control but I recently had issues trying to enable telnet on a server. Typically its pretty straightforward.
 yum install telnet-server chkconfig telnet on chkconfig xinetd on service xinetd start  Unfortunately for me this was not working. Every time I tried to telnet to the host after enabling it I would get an error message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redhats&amp;#8217; init is teh suck</title>
      <link>https://nickanderson.github.io/2009/07/06/redhats-init-is-teh-suck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2009 00:56:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickanderson.github.io/2009/07/06/redhats-init-is-teh-suck/</guid>
      <description>I recently had to write an init script for our continuous integration systems remote build agent. Of course this agent is a java jar and does not write its own pidfile. On debian or gentoo (yes I used to rice it) this would not have been an issue. Both have and use start-stop-daemon in their init scripts. start-stop-daemon actually understands that not every process you might want to daemonize writes its own pidfile and thus gives you the ability to daemonize a process, capture its pid, and write a pidfile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cpanel WHM inside Centos 5.1 domU</title>
      <link>https://nickanderson.github.io/2008/05/01/cpanel-whm-inside-centos-51-domu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2008 00:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickanderson.github.io/2008/05/01/cpanel-whm-inside-centos-51-domu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I needed to install cpanel inside of one of my Centos 5.1 domU. The centos install was bootstrapped by the default rinse configuration (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xen-tools.org/software/xen-tools/&#34;&gt;xen-tools&lt;/a&gt; with my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cmdln.org/images/wp-content/uploads/2008/04/rinse-centos5.patch&#34;&gt;patch&lt;/a&gt; that you can see from a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cmdln.org/2008/04/25/xen-installing-centos-5-domu-inside-debian-etch-dom0-with-xen-tools-and-rinse-the-patch-to-fix-it/&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;). If you follow the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cpanel.net/docs/vps/&#34;&gt;install docs&lt;/a&gt; you will have tried to uninstall openldap etc &amp;#8230;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xen installing Centos 5 domU inside debian etch dom0 with xen-tools and rinse: the patch to fix it</title>
      <link>https://nickanderson.github.io/2008/04/25/xen-installing-centos-5-domu-inside-debian-etch-dom0-with-xen-tools-and-rinse-the-patch-to-fix-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2008 18:12:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickanderson.github.io/2008/04/25/xen-installing-centos-5-domu-inside-debian-etch-dom0-with-xen-tools-and-rinse-the-patch-to-fix-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After more testing I have narrowed the issue that I left off with to a problem with the yum conf inside of the chroot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>