<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>howto on </title>
    <link>https://cmdln.org/tags/howto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in howto on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2008 18:12:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cmdln.org/tags/howto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Get around that pesky firewall filtering with tsocks</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2008/02/12/get-around-that-pesky-firewall-filtering-with-tsocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2008 18:12:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2008/02/12/get-around-that-pesky-firewall-filtering-with-tsocks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I generally don’t have any issues knowing someone might be snooping on a bit of my traffic. However there are times you may want your traffic to be a bit more private. For example if your boss is a raging tyrant and your looking for a new job, and you know the sky would fall if he found out you emailed or happened to be on Career Builder or for that matter had even the slightest idea of abandoning him. Yes I am recounting something from my past, hey at least its distant past :). So if you find yourself in that situation read on for how to use tsocks and ssh as a simple proxy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zabbix 1.4.4 from source on Debian Etch</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2008/02/10/zabbix-144-from-source-on-debian-etch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 02:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2008/02/10/zabbix-144-from-source-on-debian-etch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This guide will walk you through installing Zabbix 1.4.4 from source on debian etch. 1.4.4 has many improvements over what is currently available in apt, and its not hard so you might as well do it this way. *Note: this walkthrough assumes that you will be running the zabbix database on the same machine as the frontend. You dont have to obviously, just do the mysql setup on whatever db server you are using and point the necessary things to it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
