<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nginx on </title>
    <link>http://www.cmdln.org/tags/nginx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nginx on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2010 23:41:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.cmdln.org/tags/nginx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nginx stub_status Zenpack</title>
      <link>http://www.cmdln.org/2010/07/09/nginx-stub_status-zenpack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2010 23:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cmdln.org/2010/07/09/nginx-stub_status-zenpack/</guid>
      <description>Nginx is a great little web server. I have posted previously about using it as a reverse proxy. Weather your using it as a reverse proxy or as a normal webserver you will probably eventually want to know what its doing over time so you can adjust resources as necessary.
The other day I threw together a Zenpack to make it easier to setup monitoring on new Zenoss instances. It contains a command data source &amp;#8220;check_nginx_ng&amp;#8221; which is a slightly modified version of Chris Kellys check_nginx_ng which in turn was based on check_nginx by Mike Adolphs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transparent dynamic reverse proxy with nginx</title>
      <link>http://www.cmdln.org/2009/07/12/transparent_dynamic-reverse-proxy-with-nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2009 17:29:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cmdln.org/2009/07/12/transparent_dynamic-reverse-proxy-with-nginx/</guid>
      <description>A while back I wrote about using Apache as a dynamic reverse proxy. Anyone who has done even minimal research into web servers knows that Apache is the swiss army knife. It trys to be everything for everyone, and like a swiss army knife may not be as good as a more refined too at least as far as efficiency is concerned.
Here is the situation. You have a single pinhole into your private network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving debians nginx init script</title>
      <link>http://www.cmdln.org/2009/04/27/improving-debians-nginx-init-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 17:14:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.cmdln.org/2009/04/27/improving-debians-nginx-init-script/</guid>
      <description>nginx is a high performance HTTP and mail proxy server written by Igor Sysoev.
I&amp;#8217;m not sure what the init scripts do for other distros but it seems a bit of an oversight to leave out checking the config file when running the init script.
Add this line to your nginx init script right after the text -x $DAEMON line to make it check the config before proceeding to start stop or restart the service.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>