<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>proxy on </title>
    <link>https://cmdln.org/tags/proxy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in proxy on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2009 17:29:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cmdln.org/tags/proxy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Transparent dynamic reverse proxy with nginx</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2009/07/12/transparent_dynamic-reverse-proxy-with-nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2009 17:29:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2009/07/12/transparent_dynamic-reverse-proxy-with-nginx/</guid>
      <description>A while back I wrote about using Apache as a dynamic reverse proxy. Anyone who has done even minimal research into web servers knows that Apache is the swiss army knife. It trys to be everything for everyone, and like a swiss army knife may not be as good as a more refined too at least as far as efficiency is concerned.
Here is the situation. You have a single pinhole into your private network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get around that pesky firewall filtering with tsocks</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2008/02/12/get-around-that-pesky-firewall-filtering-with-tsocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2008 18:12:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2008/02/12/get-around-that-pesky-firewall-filtering-with-tsocks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I generally don’t have any issues knowing someone might be snooping on a bit of my traffic. However there are times you may want your traffic to be a bit more private. For example if your boss is a raging tyrant and your looking for a new job, and you know the sky would fall if he found out you emailed or happened to be on Career Builder or for that matter had even the slightest idea of abandoning him. Yes I am recounting something from my past, hey at least its distant past :). So if you find yourself in that situation read on for how to use tsocks and ssh as a simple proxy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
