<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vmware on </title>
    <link>https://cmdln.org/tags/vmware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vmware on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 14:45:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cmdln.org/tags/vmware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Growing a root file system</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2010/07/13/growing-a-root-file-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 14:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2010/07/13/growing-a-root-file-system/</guid>
      <description>IMHO one of the great benefits of virtualization is the ability to properly size your guests. Many times 512M memory and an 8G / is plenty. Increasing memory for a virtual machine is typically pretty straight forward, but there are several options when adding disk space. Mounting the space in the file system and doing something with LVM are likely the most common paths.
Depending on the situation I typically lean toward keeping my small 8G root and mounting extra storage where needed in the file system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&amp;#8217;s not &amp;#8220;the cloud&amp;#8221; it&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;the phog&amp;#8221;</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2009/08/19/its-not-the-cloud-its-the-phog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 02:47:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2009/08/19/its-not-the-cloud-its-the-phog/</guid>
      <description>I am so very tired of hearing about “the cloud”. Over lunch the other day a co-worker decided we should just call it the phog instead since the phog does a better job of describing exactly what is meant by the cloud.
Why is phog a better description? The phog has no defined shape, you can’t see clearly in it, its different everywhere you go, and once your in the middle of it you can’t find your way out (due to marketing fluf).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slowdown VMware Bios Screen</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2008/05/03/slowdown-vmware-bios-screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2008 22:35:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2008/05/03/slowdown-vmware-bios-screen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Working with virtual machines after having worked with physical machines can be a wonderful experience. Wonderful that is until the bios scree blows past you several times.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patching vmware for 2.6.24</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2008/04/09/patching-vmware-for-2624/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2008 18:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2008/04/09/patching-vmware-for-2624/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So as I previously said I have updated to Hardy Haron and along with it comes a new kernel that does not work out of the box with vmware. You need to patch your vmnet and vmmon sources to get it working again. So I went ahead and wrote a script to make the process a bit faster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vmware disk recovery in linux</title>
      <link>https://cmdln.org/2008/02/07/vmware-disk-recovery-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2008 03:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cmdln.org/2008/02/07/vmware-disk-recovery-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have ever had an issue with vmware or if you have been afraid of using vmware for fear that if something goes horribly wrong you may not be able to extract the information from your vmware image then this information should help you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
